So now that we covered a lot and we have our build control set up and can build a burger, let's create that
imdi ok ey kapladk ve kurulum kontrolmz yaptk ve Bullah
modal which allows us to display an order summary. This modal should be shown once we click checkout
Berger, aada eklememiz gereken Check out dmesini tkladmzda bir zet discommode modalnn sipariini
button which we also have to add below our build controls.
grntlememizi salayan modaleti oluturmasna izin vereceiz. kontrolleri.
So these are the things I want to do next, add this checkout button to the build controls and add this modal
Bu yzden denetimleri oluturmak iin kontrol dmesini tklatp temel olarak kendiminkine girmesi gereken
which should basically wrap itself around some kind of order summary which probably should also go into
sipari zetinin bir tr etrafnda sarlmas gereken modal olan eklemek iin bir sonraki
its own component.
admlar yapmak istiyorum.
Let's build this step by step and let's start with that
kiniz de adm adm ilerleyelim ve balayalm.
checkout button. For that,
BOTTEN iin baba gz atn.
let's go to the build controls because I want to add the checkout button at the bottom of these controls
Teknelerin kontrollerine gidelim, nk bu kontrollerin altndaki check-out butonuna eklemek istiyorum.
and there we can now simply add this, well this button in the end which should show this modal in the
Ve sonunda, sonunda bu modeli gstermek iin bu butonu da
end.
ekleyebilirim.
So what I'll add here is a normal button, normal html button element or jsx as it always is here
Yani her yl normal bir HGL dme eleman normal dme veya J her zaman olduu gibi X'dir.
but you know what I mean with html and this button should say order now.
Ama kemoterapyla ne demek istediimi biliyorsun, bu da emir vermeli.
Now I'm going to put this caption in all caps but that of course is optional,
imdi bu baln tamamn byk harflerle yazacam, ancak tabii ki istee baldr.
you can style this button and the text on the button in whichever way you want.
Bu dmeyi ve dmenin metnini istediiniz ekilde stilde dzenleyebilirsiniz.
Now the button,
imdi dme.
speaking of styling should of course also receive some styles.
Durdurmann konumas tabii ki de baz stiller alacaktr.
So let's open build controls and attach to this file,
Bu yzden her iki denetimi de ap bu dosyaya yapalm.
you will find the css code for this button.
Bu dmenin s kodunu bulacaksnz.
Here I simply added the order button css class,
Burada sipari dmesini Zia'nn S snfn ekleyeceim.
then I added the hover and active styles. The disabled style which we want to use when we can't order the
Daha sonra fareyle aktif olmayan aktif Stahl' devre d brakma stilini ekledik. Bu stil, bir burgeri emrettiinde kullanacamz
burger because we haven't added any ingredients and a little animation here which will simply animate the button
devre d brakma stilidir. nk herhangi bir katk maddesi eklemedik ve Elham sadece dmeyi yapan herhangi bir iftlemeyi yapmad.
once it does become active. Now with that added to the css file
Bir kez aktif hale geldikten sonra bu tutum faul olarak grlr.
make sure to save the updated buildControls css file
Gncellenmi cvata kontrolleri C-s'yi aadaki gibi kaydettiinizden emin olun.
and now we can add our class name to that button and there, it is the css class name
Ve imdi snf dmesini adn ekleyebiliriz ve snf ad var.
I just added in the css file
Ben sadece Cs'ye ekleyin.
order button and simply check the file to confirm this OrderButton,
Sipari dmesini tklayn ve bu sipari dmesini onaylamak iin dosyay kontrol etmeniz yeterlidir.
this css class.
Bu bir snf.
So this is the button style, now to disable this button,
Bu dmeyi devre d brakmak iin dme stili imdi de geerli.
we need to check whether all ingredients have an amount of 0 or if at least one of the ingredients
Tm katk maddelerinin miktar 0 olan veya ieriklerin en az bir tanesi 1'de olup
is at 1 which would make this button activated because then, we could of course click it.
olmadn kontrol etmemiz gerekecek ve bu dme etkinleecektir, nk o zaman elbette tklayabiliriz.
So this logic to check whether this button should be active so whether we can purchase the burger or not
nk burada belirtmek istediimiz her malzemeden ne kadarn bildiimiz yer. Bu burgere eklemek iin.
of course should managed in the burger builder container because that is where we have the state, that
Nerede olursa olsun mantk denetimi yapyor, ancak gemi etkinleiyor, bylelikle burgeri
is where we know how much of each ingredient we want to add to this burger.
kovalyor, tabii ki ynetilmemeli ve burger Boulder konteynerini kullanmamz gerekiyor,
What we need to know here is the total amount of all ingredients
Burada bilmemiz gereken ey, tm malzemelerin toplam miktardr.
so basically a sum of all the ingredients and I will simply add a new property where I will say
Yani temel olarak btn maddelerin bir toplam ve Shea'nn masasna syleyeceim yeni bir
purchasable and I will set this to false initially.
zellik ekleyeceim ve bunu balangta zorla balatacam.
Now purchasable should simply become true
Artk satn alnabilir nitelikler doru olur.
once we can buy this purchasable, once we can buy this burger so once at least one ingredient is one or
Bir keresinde, bir keresinde bir ya da daha fazla en az bir madde olan onun burgerini alabileceimiz bir kez bu
more.
satn alnabilir.
Now I will add a new method to the burger builder updatePurchaseState,
imdi, kovalamaca durumu bana burger oluturucuya yeni bir yntem ekleyeceim.
any name you like does it here and I want to call this method
Beendiiniz herhangi bir ad burada yapyor ve bu yntemi armak istiyorum.
at the end of addIngredient and removeIngredientHandler to then simply check whether we need to
Bir maddenin sonunda ve medyan ileyiciyi younlatrmak iin sadece ikiye mi ihtiyacmz var m yoksa
or whether we should turn purchasable to true or to false.
satn alnabilirlii Doruya m yoksa yanl m evirmeliyiz diye kontrol edin.
Therefore here, I want to check the ingredients I have in my state. So I will create a new object here
Bu nedenle, burada sahip olduum malzemeleri kontrol etmek istiyorum, bylece bu devletin bir kopyasn oluturmak
to create a copy of this.state.
iin yeni bir nesne yaratacam.
ingredients.
Malzemeler.
Now I need to sum up all the values here,
imdi burada tm deerleri zetlemeliyim.
now that is super easy to do in the end, what I need to do is I need to turn this object here into an
Sonunda yapmak son derece kolay olan ey u ki bu nesneyi buraya
array again, into an array of these values here.
burada bu deerlerin bir dizisine bir dizi haline getirmeliyim.
Now for that, what I can do is I can create some constant where I take my javascript object object and
imdi bunun iin yapabileceim ey, benim javascript nesne nesnemi aldm yerde bir sabit yaratabilirim ve
there I use keys again and pass my ingredients to it
oradaki tular tekrar kullanyorum ve ieriklerimi ona iletiyorum.
and this will again create an array of string entries,
Ve bu yine bir dizge dizisi yaratacak ve.
salad, bacon, cheese and so on.
Salata pastrmas peyniri vb.
Now I said that I need these values here though so the amounts of the ingredients, not the names.
imdi burada bu deerlere ihtiyacm olduunu syledim, yle ki ierikler miktar adlar deil.
Well we can simply map this array into the array
Peki bu diziyi diziye basite eleyebiliriz.
we need, so I'll do this in a new line to make it easier to read. The map method of course still receives the key
Tabii harita yntemini okumay kolaylatrmak iin yeni bir izgi tasarlamamz gerekiyor elbette yine de anahtar
and then this is used in or
alyorsunuz ve daha sonra bu Word'de kullanlmaktadr.
the function we passed to the map method receives the key here should say and then we can use this to return
Sakia'nn ald harita yntemine aktardmz ilevi sylemeliyiz ve bunu yeni deeri
new value and replace the old value which was the property name, salad and so on with that new value.
dndrmek ve salata mlkiyet ad olan eski deeri ve bu yeni deeri deitirmek iin kullanabiliriz.
And here I simply wanted to return ingredients and there the value for a given key
Ve burada sadece maddeleri geri getirmek istedim ve orada belirli bir anahtarn deeri var.
and this will be the amount because with ingredients and this notation, I'm accessing a certain property
Ve bu madde miktar ve bu gsterim maddelerin nesne nesne belirli bir
in the ingredients object, igKey is salad, bacon and so on
mlkiyet eriiyorum nedeniyle olacak IGY anahtar salata kabartma vb.
so I'm basically getting these values, the numbers and that is what I return for each key.
Bu yzden temelde bu deerleri saylarla alyorum ve her anahtar iin geri dndm ey bu.
So now I have an array of values,
imdi bir dizi deerim var.
now all I need to do is call reduce to again reduce this array
imdi tek yapmam gereken, azalmay desire'yi azaltmak iin armaktr.
but this time not to flatten the array but to turn it into a single number,
u anda diziyi dzletirmek deil, tek bir sayya dntrmek.
the sum of all ingredients. For that, we'll have a starting number of 0 and then we have a function which
Bunun iin tm ieriklerin toplam, 0'n balang saysna sahip olacak ve bu ite, bu
is executed on each element in this mapped array. In this function,
elenen dizideki her bir e zerinde altrlan bir ileve sahiptik.
I get new sum and the individual element and keep in mind, sum simply is the constantly updated
Baz bireysel elerden yeni oluyorum ve bazlarnn sade srekli gncellendiini unutmayn.
current sum up until the current iteration where this function is executed
u anki toplam, bozulmalarn yrtld geerli yineleme kadar.
and once this function was executed on all array elements, sum is the final result. And here I'll simply
toplam art e dndrlr ve unutmayn ki e bir saydr nk burada eritiimiz de-deerdir.
return the current sum plus the element and keep in mind element is a number because it is the value
Ve bir kez bu fonksiyon tm dizi elemanlarnda yrtldnde, sonu son sonutur ve
we accessed here.
burada sadece mevcut
With that, I get a sum constant which is zero if we have no ingredients added or any other number representing
Bununla birlikte, hibir katk maddesi eklenmediyse, toplam ieriini temsil eden herhangi bir say yoksa, sfr olan bir
the total amount of ingredients,
toplam sabiti elde ediyorum.
and with that I can simply call set state and set
Ve bununla sadece ayarlanm durum diyebilir ve onu ayarlayabilirim.
purchasable too
O yapabiliyor.
and now it depends on whoever has sum is greater than zero or not,
Ve imdi, bazlarnn sfrdan byk olup olmadna bal.
so we'll set it to sum greater 0. This is either
Bu yzden biraz daha 0 0 olarak ayarlayacaz.
true or false
DORU YA DA YANLI.
and it is true if we have at least one ingredient, then purchasable is true
Ve eer satn alnabilir doruysa en az bir madde ieriyorsa dorudur.
and that is exactly the behavior I want.
Ve bu tam olarak istediim davran.
So now with that, we got purchasable and we can now pass this down to build controls
imdi onunla satn alabileceimiz bir ey var ve imdi bunu kemer kontrollerine geirebiliriz.
so let's add a new property, let's also name the property purchasable maybe and let's bind the property
yleyse yeni bir mlk ekleyelim de mlkiyetin satn alnabilir olduunu belki de adlandralm ve mlk
to this state,
bu duruma balayn.
purchasable.
Satn alnabilir.
And with that, we passed the information about whether we can check this burger out and pay for it or
bununla biz bu burgeri kontrol edip edemeyeceimiz ya da deyemeyeceimiz hakknda bilgi verdik.
not.
Ve
down to the build controls where I can now take this information to disable this button or well, enable
imdi bu dmeyi devre d brakmak veya iyi etkinletirmek iin bu bilgileri alabileceim
it.
kabark kontrollere.
So let me split this over mutiple lines and bind disabled of this html button element,
Bu yzden model hatlar zerinden paralamama izin verin ve HVM l dmesi eleman devre d brakn.
again it is jsx but it will render a button in the end.
Yine GSX, ancak sonunda bir dme oluturacak.
Let's bind these two props and there it was
Bu iki sopay balayalm orada oldu.
purchasable what we just set up.
Hazrladmz eylerden satn alnabilir.
Now if we save this and we go back to a running application, we have this order now button down there,
var, satn alnabilir olmamal, ancak bir ekilde doru ekilde iletilmemelidir.
though it is enabled here and it shouldn't be, so purchasable somehow isn't passed on correctly.
imdi bunu kaydedip, almakta olan bir uygulamaya geri dnersek, burada etkinletirildiyse de u an burada dmesi
Let me quickly have a look at what's wrong,
Neyin yanl gittiine hzl bir ekilde gz atalm.
I identified the problem, purchasable of course is true if the button, if the burger is purchasable, disable
Elbette satn alnabilir problemi tespit ettim doruysa dme burger satn alnabilir ise
should be set to true though if it's not purchasable.
bu bir. m. Satn alnabilir deilse True olarak ayarlanmaldr.
So we simply have to invert this here,
Bu yzden unu sadece burada sylemeliyiz.
so add exclamation mark in front of props.purchasable and now the button should be disabled.
Bylece, pervanenin satn alnabilmesi iin nlem iareti ekleyin ve imdi dme devre d braklmaldr.
It of course never becomes active though because we never call the nice little helper method
Elbette asla faal olmaz, nk asla gzel yardmc metodu aramyoruz.
we created, this update purchase state method,
Bu gncelleme, kovalamaca usulne gre oluturuldu.
we never call it. We should call it after running
Buna asla adn vermedik, kotuktan sonra aramalyz.
addIngredientHandler or removeIngredientHandler, so there I'll then also execute this update purchase
Ed Ingredion ileyicisini veya Reagen ileyicisini kaldrarak daha sonra bu gncellemeyi kovalamaca
state, the same on the end of the removeIngredientHandler. And with that added,
durumuna gre Ingredion ileyicisini kaldrmann sonunda ayn ekilde yrtebilir ve bor ekledi.
if we now save this, we should see that the button is
imdi onu kurtarrsak onu grmeliyiz.
disabled but as soon as I add one ingredient, it stays disabled,
Ama bir bileen ekledikten sonra bu devre d kalr.
only once I add a second one, it becomes active.
Bir keresinde ikinci bir tane vardmda aktif olur.
Now why is that? Do you spot the error?
imdi neden bu hatay buluyorsun?
It has something to do with the update purchase state method, the problem is that the ingredients which
nedenle bir kere ierikleri kopyalayp analiz edersek, yalnzca iinde eski bir kelime bulabiliriz.
I'm analyzing is of course my old state here. Now due to the way set state works, when we execute update
Gncelleme ile ilgili bir ey var Chase ncesi yntemlerle sorun u ki, analiz edeceim unsurlar elbette eski
purchase state, we might not get the updated ingredients and therefore, once we copy the ingredients
durumumuzdur nk imdi elde edemediim kovalamaca durumu iin gncelleme yrttmde durumun nasl ayarlandna
and analyze them, we might simply get an outdated version.
bal olarak alyor gncellenen ierikler ve bu
Now we can of course simply fix this by passing the updated ingredients we have in add and remove ingredient
phesiz elimizden geleni, elimizdeki gncel maddeleri geirerek bunu dzeltip hindyler maddesini
handler anyways
ekleyip kaldrabiliriz.
to the update purchase state method and expect to get ingredients there,
Q Gncelleme bana kovalad durum yntemi ve orada maddeler almak iin bekliyoruz.
so ingredients. And now we can simply use these ingredients inside this method instead of the copy from
Yani maddeler ve imdi biz sadece bu yntemle devletten kopyalamak iin bu
the state.
malzemeleri kullanabilirsiniz.
Now if we save this right on the first item we add, it becomes active and we have to remove all ingredients
imdi bunu ilk maddeye kaydedersek onu aktif hale getirir ve dmeyi tekrar devre d brakmak iin
to disable the button again
tm ierikleri kaldrmamz gerekir.
and there you also see this nice animation.
Ve orada bu gzel animasyonu gryorsun.
So we get the button, this is step number one,
Bylece alt basamaa bir numara oluyoruz.
now in the next step, I want to also add a modal to display the order summary and not just show the button.
imdi sradaki admda, yalnzca sipari zetini grntlemek ve dmeyi gstermek iin bir modal eklemek istiyorum.
So let's move on that in the next lecture.
O halde bir sonraki konferansta devam edelim.